(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-17T12:33:08.079606",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ねえ その 君はさ 私に ちょっと興味ないの?
Hey, aren't you a little interested in me?
ああ そう じゃあ いいから忘れて いや やっぱ忘れないで...
Ah, is that so? Then forget it—no, wait, don't forget...
ああ もう どうして こんなに君推しなのに 気づかれない
Ah geez, why won't you notice how much I stan you?
ほんともどかしいわ!
It's so frustrating!
えっ そんな 聞いてないって 知らないって
Eh? "I never heard that," "I didn't know,"
私 全部全部を わかってたいの
I want to know everything, absolutely everything!
ダメだって? そんなこと言われても
"You can't"? Even if you tell me that,
意味わかんないじゃん!
that makes no sense at all!
「不可解現象」「異常上昇」 「どこがいいの?」なんて よく聞かれるけどさ
"Inexplicable phenomenon," "abnormal surge," "What's so good about them?" people often ask, but...
わからないでいいよ
You don't have to understand.
愛で 溢れて溢れて ああ 触れて 止まらないだけ
Overflowing with love, ah, touching—I just can't stop.
つまらないド星論 飽きない超恋愛論
Boring common sense, insatiable hyper-romance theory.
さあ、どうする?ダーリン?
Now, what will you do, darling?
ああ もう 君はさ 僕に愛想尽えちゃってしょうがない
Ah geez, you're utterly sick of me, and I can't help it.
いつも抜け駆け足踏みするのは 忍びないけど
Sneaking ahead and stepping out of line is hard to hold back, but
心いったりきたり 泣き疲れちゃっても困っちゃうし
My heart wanders back and forth, and getting exhausted from crying is troublesome too,
いつまで待ったって答えないからさ
since you never give an answer no matter how long I wait.
僕は今日も逃げるのさ
So today, I'm running away again!
フラフラ危機一髪 あなたは僕の運命の人
Wobbling on the brink, you are my destined person!
許してよ こんなの あんまりじゃーん!
Forgive me, isn't this just too much?!
いや そんな 決められないって 選べないって
No, "I can't decide," "I can't choose,"
僕は全部全部を 愛してたいの
I want to love everything, absolutely everything!
最低だって?そんなこと言われても
"That's the worst"? Even if you say that,
別に銃口承知
I'm fully aware and prepared!
ラブソングに冗談要相談 「何がダメなの?」なんてよく聞かれるけどさ
Asking for jokes on love songs, "What's wrong with that?" people often ask, but...
他人事もいいところの 愛にあたって
Meeting love in someone else's affairs,
暮らしてすぐ直ぐに立ち上がるだけ
living through it and getting right back up.
奇想天外!分かっているのかい? 皆してあーだの こーだの言っちゃって
Outrageous! Do you understand? Everyone saying this and that!
愛know味?チェリー味? テンプラダメね 女の子面倒くさい!
Love-know flavor? Cherry flavor? Tempura is no good, girls are such a pain!
桜花爛漫 猛吹雪でも 天真爛漫 冷静になれと
Even in cherry blossom storms and raging blizzards, stay pure and keep your cool!
不運を疎んでも難アリなやつさ
Even if bad luck is resented, they're troublesome!
半信／半疑
Half-believing, half-doubting,
ご愛嬌、大惨事？
adorable, or a disaster?
止めどないこの愛のアイウエオ
This unending love's AIUEO!
教えて 一揃って するくせっ毛
Teach me, all lined up, naturally curly hair
気絶しない？全然しょないってば
Won't you faint? Not at all!
私もっと全部全部をわかっていたいの
I want to know everything, absolutely everything!
ダメだよって？そんなこと言われても
You say "No"? Even if you tell me that,
意味かんないじゃん 「不可解現象」「異常上昇」
It makes no sense! "Unexplainable phenomenon," "abnormal rise"
全く、どうしようもない君に天罰を
Good grief, divine punishment for someone as hopeless as you!
だらしなくらいがちょうどいい
Being a little sloppy is just right
愛が溢れて溢れてとまらないっ
Love overflows and overflows, it won't stop!
ともう、もう、いい加減にして！
Come on, already, give me a break!
身体よ狂えルナティックなんて説明しよう
Body, go crazy, what a lunatic explanation
とりあえず私だけ見つめてよ ねぇ！
For now, just look at me, hey!
心キロキロ許さない
Heart fluctuating, I won't forgive you
一瞬でも 一秒でも 側を感じていたい
Even for a moment, even for a second, I want to feel close
だから一緒にいて
So stay with me
Hello, hi everyone, halo semuanya,
minasan konbanwa and welcome
to my 3D reveal.
Woo! Have you guys seen my room? I sang AIUE, it's one of my favorite songs, yay!
Tadi kalian lihat kan? Aku udah nyanyi dan dance, and look at my room! Oh my god, guys!
Did you guys see that? I already sang and danced, and look at my room! Oh my god, guys!
Guys, ingat gak kalian pas debut? Ini dari horbo bisa jadi sekarang, guys! Bisa di sini!
Guys, do you remember my debut? This can go from horbo to now, guys! Right here!
Kalau aku bisa, kenapa kalian tidak bisa? Gila, motivational kriz! Oh my god!
If I can do it, why can't you guys? Crazy, motivational kriz! Oh my god!
Okay, look at this! Look at this, what is this? Do you guys know what is this? Yes, this is a cowboy hat!
Karena aku suka pakai itu, apa sih? Cowboy emote. I like to use a cowboy emote a lot and I have a cowboy hat with me now!
Because I like to use that, what is it? Cowboy emote. I like to use a cowboy emote a lot and I have a cowboy hat with me now!
And look at my table! There's a lot of stuffs here. Oh my god, and who is this?
And look at my table! There's a lot of stuff here. Oh my god, and who is this?
Who is this? Apa gak ini toaster, kunk?
Who is this? What is this toaster, kunk?
Is this the real comeback of toaster kunk? Oh my goodness! Okay, I'm gonna I'm gonna be making a toast real quick.
Is this the real comeback of toaster kunk? Oh my goodness! Okay, I'm gonna be making a toast real quick.
Okay! Okay, I will be going back here after this.
Ghila, lihat, lihat kamar ku, guys! Lihat kamar ku, guys!
Wow, look, look at my room, guys! Look at my room, guys!
Uh so many weapons cause I am an ancient weapon. This is only befitting of an ancient weapon!
Uh, det, kooko wa? Otto! Kore wa... Kore wa fancy na! Kore wa fancy na ne!
Uh, wait, right here? Whoa! This is... This is fancy! This is fancy, huh?
Coba, nonda miyoka. Um... Um... Ummee!
Let's try drinking it. Um... Um... Delicious!
Okay, that was that was delicious. We getting fancy here. Ooh!
Gochu so samadeshitato.
Thank you for the meal.
Okay! Apakah tosku sudah jadi? Ore? Wait, what?
Okay! Is the toast ready? Wait, what?
Ini, ini kenapa? Wait, why, wait, why? Lagi 3D reveal jangan ngebak, why?
Wait, why is this? Wait, wait, wait! Why? During 3D reveal, don't bug out, why?
Aku tahu aku bug tester, tapi jangan ngebak! Wah! Wah, tunggu!
I know I'm a bug tester, but don't bug out! Wow! Wow, wait!
Tunggu, sebentar! Bugnya nanti, bugnya nanti, jangan sekarang! Ini lagi 3D reveal kocak! Oh my god!
Wait, hold on! Bug later, bug later, not right now! This is 3D reveal, you funny! Oh my god!
Don't bug on me! It's my 3D reveal! Oh! Oh my god!
Aduh, pengen, I just wanted to eat one toast!
Ah, I wanted to, I just wanted to eat one toast!
And this is what I have to go through? I know I'm a bug tester, but not like this, man!
Oh my god, let's put my hat first. Let's put my hat back.
All right, okay, let's eat this one toast.
Um... Um... Oishii! This is so good, guys, as expected from toaster kunk!
Um... Um... Delicious! This is so good, guys, as expected from Toaster-kun!
Thank you so much, toaster kunk! Ah, oishii kore! Arigato! Arigato na, toaster kunk!
Thank you so much, Toaster-kun! Ah, this is delicious! Thank you! Thank you, Toaster-kun!
Oh! What? Who is that?
Ada dederi, ada caller PC siapa? Siapa itu? Who is that?
Wait, is there a PC call? Who is that? Who is that? Who's that?
Hello?
Moshimoshi? Moshimoshi? Hello?
Hachoo! Hachoo! Ha-heng!
Achoo! Achoo! Ah-choo!
Ha-heng! Perkenalan dirimu, Ha-heng, siapa?
Ah-choo! Introduce yourself, Ha-heng, who are you?
Omedetou! Arigato, siri! Omedetou!
Congratulations! Thank you! Congratulations!
Siapa namamu?
What's your name?
Aku...
I...
idih, jangan risau, ID gen satu!
Ew, don't worry, ID Gen 1!
Wih, der, dan di sebelahnya ada jamet,
Whoa, Der, and next to her is Jamet—
eh, bukan, siapa namamu? Bukan jamet kan?
uh, no, what's your name? Not Jamet, right?
Jamet, jamet. Aku Omed, nggak.
Jamet, Jamet. I'm Omed, nope.
Aku Omed, Kaelah. Omed, okey.
I'm Omed, Kaelah. Omed, okay.
Omed dua orang. Omed dua orang, ya.
Two Omeds. Two Omeds, yeah.
ID gen tiga!
ID Gen 3!
Wih, Risu, Senpai, and Kaelah, thank you so much for coming.
Whoa, Risu Senpai and Kaelah, thank you so much for coming.
How do you guys like my room? Bagaimana kamarku?
How do you guys like my room? How is my room?
Gila banget, ya?
It's insane, right?
Lihat deh di meja itu...
Look at that table...
Mau mau apa? Mau looting!
You want what? You want to loot!
Jangan looting aku, aku dari hobo bisa berusaha sekeras ini untuk dapetin kamar yang sekeren ini.
Don't loot me, I was a hobo and worked hard
to get a room as cool as this.
Gila, bagi-bagilah.
Crazy, share some.
Widih, guys, di meja ini aku banyak banget, aku lumayan banyak senjata ya guys.
Whoa, guys, on this table I have a lot,
I have quite a lot of weapons, guys.
Aku main banyak, ditanyain senjata, aduh.
I played a lot, asked about weapons, oh.
Pokoknya ada banyak deh, di situ ada, ada gan dan ada kris, oh my god.
Anyway there are many, there's a gun and a kris, oh my god.
Just like me, for real, for real.
Oh my god, but I have something even more cooler.
Aku ada yang lebih keren, guys. What is that? Apa tu?
I have something even cooler, guys. What is that? What's that?
Taran! Widih!
Taran! Whoa!
Apa ini? Toedpaisen? Ini apa toedpaisen?
What is this? Two-finger-sen?
What is this two-finger-sen?
Itu, itu adalah dagger sakti!
That, that is a mystical dagger!
Dagger sakti, saktinya begini ya guys.
Mystical dagger, the mysticism is like this, guys.
Wih, keren, keren, keren. Kalau gitu nih, kalau gitu nih, sekali ya, sekalian.
Whoa, cool, cool, cool. In that case, in that case,
once, all at once.
Apa?
What?
Karena sudah ada dagger yang sangat keren, aku mau request pose, boleh ya?
Since there's already a really cool dagger,
I want to request a pose, is that okay?
Boleh dong. Let's go, asyik!
Sure. Let's go, awesome!
Kalau gitu ya, langsung aja nih, aku dapet image gitu.
In that case, right away, I got an image.
Kalau Anya itu dapet image berpose kayak ini.
If Anya gets an image posing like this.
Kayak sebelum fighting gitu, kayak idol-idol pose gitu, kayak di fighting game gitu.
Like before fighting, like idol poses,
like in a fighting game.
Betul, oke.
Right, okay.
Coba, coba. Mana ya pose? Pose kayak gini kah?
Try, try. Where's the pose?
Is the pose like this?
Wih, sangar, guys. Mantap!
Whoa, fierce, guys. Awesome!
Mantap sih, wih, gila, keren banget. Ada satu lagi by the way, ada satu lagi, guys.
That's awesome, whoa, crazy, really cool.
There's one more by the way, there's one more, guys.
Apa ini? Apa ini?
What's this? What's this?
Aku juga mau request, aku juga mau request dari Kaelah juga, dari Kaelah juga.
I also want to request, I also want to request
from Kaelah too, from Kaelah too.
Apa? Bentar, aku ambil dulu.
What? Wait, I'll grab it first.
Taran! Apa ini?
Taran! What is this?
Gila enggak sih, keren banget enggak sih ini?
Isn't it crazy, isn't this really cool?
Ini revolver, guys. Ini revolver ala Anya ya guys.
This is a revolver, guys.
This is a revolver ala Anya, guys.
Mau request apa Kaelah tadi? Kita mau request.
What did Kaelah want to request earlier?
We want to request.
Boleh, boleh. Mau enggak kayak itu? Kayak yang di cover-cover film gitu, biasanya di movie cover gitu.
Sure, sure. Want it like that?
Like in movie covers, usually in movie covers.
Nah, jadi kamu hadap belakang dulu, kamu hadap belakang dulu.
So, you face backwards first,
you face backwards first.
Hadap belakang? Oke. Terus kepalanya hadap depan, muka-muka hadap depan.
Face backwards? Okay.
Then your head faces forward, your face faces forward.
Oh, kayaknya kamu tertawa deh apa yang kamu maksud.
Oh, I think you're laughing at what you mean.
Gitu. Terus tangannya kayak ke atas gitu. Itu bisa buat nembak enggak tuh?
Like that. Then your hands like upwards.
Can that be used for shooting?
Iya, bisa buat nembak dong.
Yeah, it can be used for shooting.
Mau lihat nih? Coba dong, coba dong. Gimana?
Want to see this? Try it, try it. How?
Wih, wih. Gimana tuh menurut kamu?
Whoa, whoa. How is that according to you?
Iya, iya. Coba, coba posenya. Wih, gila.
Yeah, yeah. Try, try the pose. Whoa, crazy.
Oke, gimana, guys? Keren banget. Thank you so much for coming.
Okay, how is it, guys? Really cool.
Thank you so much for coming.
Dan, kris satu ini, guys. Gila, keren banget pokoknya.
And this one kris, guys.
Crazy, it's really cool anyway.
Makasih banyak loh, guys, sudah datang. Thank you, thank you, Anya.
Thank you so much, guys, for coming.
Thank you, thank you, Anya.
Thank you! Good thank you.
Bye-bye! Arigatou!
Bye-bye! Thank you!
Nah, jadi itu ya, guys, Risu Senpai dan Jamet—eh, bukan, Kaelah.
So that's it, guys, Risu Senpai
and Jamet—uh, no, Kaelah.
Thank you so much to Risu Senpai and Kaelah for coming to my 3D showcase.
Thank you so much to Risu Senpai and Kaelah
for coming to my 3D showcase.
Apakah kita ada guest lagi? Do we have any more guests, I wonder?
Do we have any more guests?
Do we have any more guests, I wonder?
Hmm, oh! Kita, kita, kita.
Hmm, oh! We, we, we.
Mana ini? Mana ini? Wah, ngebug, guys. Kok ngebug, guys?
Where is this? Where is this?
Wow, it's lagging, guys. Why is it lagging, guys?
Anya!
Miko-senpai dayo! Miko-senpai dayo! Kiteitayo!
It's Miko-senpai! It's Miko-senpai!
I came!
Sonokoe wa! Miko-senpai nyaha-hello!
That voice! Miko-senpai nyaha-hello!
Yay, yay, yay!
Ah, kita-kunai. Ojama shimasu.
Ah, you came. Excuse me.
Ya, kite kurete arigatou gozaimasu! Hazuka!
Yeah, thank you for coming! Embarrassing!
Jikoshoukai. Etto... Anya-hello! Hololive... Japan!
Self-introduction. Uh... Anya-hello!
Hololive... Japan!
JP no elitanya... Sakura Miko-nesu! Yoroshiku onegai shimasu!
JP's elite... Sakura Miko-nesu!
Please treat me well!
え？
Huh?
ホルライブイヌ？
Hololive Inu?
の、の、の、の。の？ Not INU!
No, no, no, no. No? Not INU!
ジャップ？じゃない、じゃっぷですか？
Jap? No, is it Jap?
いや、あ、IDです。インドネシア、日本、インドネシア、あれ？
No, ID. Indonesia, Japan, Indonesia... wait?
うますぎるな ちょっと。みこよりもなんかじゃないのってレベルで出る。
You're too good. You're at a level that might surpass Miko.
いやいやいやいや、そんな。いや、あやちっちゃいのおめでとう！
No, no, no, no way. Congrats on being small, Anya!
可愛いよ、みこ、お姉さんだからね。お姉さんなの？
You're cute, Miko, 'cause you're an older sister. Are you an older sister?
えー、可愛い！可愛い！
Eh, cute! So cute!
え、なんでみこのこと呼んでくれたの？
Eh, why did you invite Miko?
え、やっぱここ最近めちゃくちゃ仲いいじゃないですか、我々。
Well, lately we've been getting super close, the two of us.
まあ、デートもしたしね。まあね、デートもしたしね。
Well, we went on a date too. Right, we went on a date.
寝顔もね、2つくれたもんね。ね？撮ってくれたもんね、寝顔ね。
You gave me two sleeping face pictures too. Right? You took pictures of my sleeping face.
めっちゃ嬉しそうだった。もう、幸せそう。この開発でみこもくれたんだよ。
You looked so happy. So blissful. Miko gave you one in this development too.
ね？優しいよねえ。やったぜ。いやあ、出れるな。
Right? So kind. Yay. Man, I can get out.
いやでも、いろんな絆がありますからね、ヘリとか。あ、そう、ジャンダルム作った。
But you know, we have various bonds, like helicopters... Ah, right, I made Jebel Musa.
あ！ありました！プーーンってやつ。バーーンってやつね。
Ah! There was! That "zooom" thing. That "bang" thing.
はい、ということで、まあ私ね、あの3Dお披露目でさ、いい絵を描きたいんですよ。
Right, so... well, I want to draw a nice picture for my 3D reveal.
絵を描きたい？そう、絵を描きたくて、みこもけど。
You want to draw a picture? Yeah, I want to draw, and Miko too, but...
お！でも、普通に絵を描くのがね、ちょっとつまんないんじゃないですか？
Oh! But wouldn't it be a bit boring to just normally draw a picture?
ということで、対決！対決したいと思って。いいんですか、みこど...
So, a showdown! We want to have a showdown. Is that okay, Miko...
みこ先輩、そう。噂によるとね、絵がうまいので。
Miko-senpai, right. Rumor has it you're good at drawing.
え？あ！まあそれはまあ、確かにJPの中では中の下ぐらいのうまさ...
Eh? Ah! Well, that's... true, among JP, maybe lower-middle tier...
まあ、うまいよね、エリートだからね。じゃあこの後見るか。
Well, you're good, since you're elite. Then let's watch it afterwards.
うん、この後見て、みこのやつ。
Yeah, let's check Miko's afterwards.
そう！でも、まだね、あの、まだまだゲストがいます！え？ゲスト！この二人！
That's right! But still, there are more guests! Eh? Guests! These two!
Introduce yourself starting from Meimei.
Yes, yes. Hello, o-hi! I'm Nanashi Mumei. I'm a member of Hololive English Council and a brown-haired Don't Care gang.
Oh, you're so cute!
And Z-ta! Hello, I'm Ouro Kronii from Hololive ID Gen 3. Yay!
でね、この後、まあイラスト、まあ絵の対決やるんですけど、まあね、あのスタッフさんからね、あの、お題ね、あのもらったんですよね。
And then, after this, well, we're doing an illustration showdown, but well, you know, we got a prompt from the staff.
あ、いいじゃないですか。でそのお題を書いて、でムメイと対決でございます。
Ah, that's great. So we write that prompt, and it's a showdown against Mumei.
So what we will be doing is that staff, staff thought up of a prompt, and me and Miko-senpai have to draw them, and Mumei and Z-ta will be the one guessing what prompt is it.
Okay! We have one minute to draw. 1 minute, 1 minute, yeah, 60 seconds. Let's draw.
1分で書きましょう。難しね。これを使います。
Let's draw it in 1 minute. Tough, huh? We'll use this.
ドン！ドン！おーー！キャンバスな！本格的ですね、姉さん。ねえ。
Bam! Bam! Ooh! A canvas! How authentic, neesan. Right.
これいいですよ。ここ座って。じゃあ座っていただいて。よしよし。
This is good. Sit here. So please take a seat. Good, good.
とりあえず、あ、ムメイとゼータ、クローズユアアイズ、cause we will be showing the prompt. みんなね！みんな今ね、
For now, Mumei and Zeta, close your eyes, cause we will be showing the prompt. Everyone! Everyone right now...
あひるに告白するスバル
Subaru confessing to a duck
あ！お！お！なるほどですね。
Ah! Oh! Oh! I see.
ストロベリーピーク？
Strawberry peak?
1分なんだよね。どうなるんかな？オッケー、オープンユアアイズ。
It's 1 minute, huh. I wonder how it'll turn out. Okay, open your eyes.
マイアイズアーオープン。おし、じゃあ始まりますか。行きましょか。
My eyes are open. Alright, shall we start? Let's go.
レディ？レディ？レディ？セット、ゴーー！オッケー！イットハズビガン！
Ready? Ready? Ready? Set, go! Okay! It has begun!
1分で描けるのこれ全て？
Can you draw all that in 1 minute?
デューユーシンク1ミニットイズイナフートゥドロウエニシング？ノー...ゼイウィルプレヴェイル。
Do you think 1 minute is enough to draw anything? No... they will prevail.
どうやって描くんだっく？
How do we even draw this?
ゼイハブソーマチパッションインゼアイズ！
They have so much passion in their eyes!
なんだって？
What was that?
エクサクトリー！ウィー、ウィー、ウィーシュッドビーエイブルトゥフィギュアディスアウト。キャニュ--
Exactly! We, we, we should be able to figure this out. Can you--
イッツメイビフィガードアウトベースドオ--アイワズアバウトトゥセイエトウー！
It's maybe figured out based o-- I was about to say it too!
これちょっと難しいぞこれ
This is a bit difficult, you know.
It could be, I don't know, something, something, something related to their emotions maybe?
It could be, I don't know, something related to their emotions maybe?
I'm not sure.
これだけにそうじ! Oh, what do you think?
Keep it like that! Oh, what do you think?
これだけにして! これだけにして!
Please keep it just like that!
Oh, it could be a hair.
What if it's the skull?
ちょっと待って! ちょっと難しいぞこれ。
Wait a minute! This is a bit difficult.
いや、これは絵心が、絵心がどうとかだから。
Well, this depends on whether someone has drawing skills.
せめて、あの、まあ、誰かだけ伝わってほしいな。
At least, um, I want someone to understand it.
そうね。オッケー。
That's right. Okay.
オッケー、オッケー。誰かを当てるのは100パーセント。
Okay, okay. Guessing who it is is 100%.
What's your to show?
What's your show to show?
オッケー。オッケー。Let's see. Anya's!
Okay. Okay. Let's see. Anya's!
Yes!
ドン! ドン!
Bam! Bam!
いやせめて、誰かだけ伝わってほしい、これは。
At least I want someone to get this!
もうね、ぶっちゃけなのよ。これ、アサルトボート。
Honestly, it's pretty obvious. This is an assault boat.
Is that a duck? I was about to say it's a duck.
Mumei, what do you think that is? I can't tell.
Come on, my masterpiece.
Who is it? Quick surprise.
え、誰? だ。ドン!
Huh, who? Bam!
Oh, it's a platypus.
これじゃねえか! カモノハシじゃねえか!
It's a platypus, isn't it?
いやいや、ちょっと伝わるよ。
No, no, it'll get across.
いや、みんな大体同じこと... I guess we'll find out.
We're probably doing the same thing. I guess we'll find out.
オッケー。オッケー。
Okay. Okay.
何をやってもカッコいいどこが?
"Whatever he does is cool" - where?
It's time for a new discussion time.
Whose prompt do you guys think this is?
Okay, Mumei can go first. All right, I think it is Subaru-senpai talking to a platypus.
Yes. Okay, it does look like a platypus. I'm going to say the same thing, except a duck maybe.
はあ、はあ、はあ。シュバシュバ。シュバシュバシュバシュバ。
Ha ha ha. Subashuba. Subashuba subashuba.
果たして、Is it wrong? Is it correct?
Is it... Is it wrong? Is it correct?
正解がどうか。どうだ? Your answer? Final answer?
Is it correct? How is it? Your answer? Final answer?
A platypus, I guess. A platypus, I guess.
It's not a platypus.
オッケー。Yeah, platypus, yeah. Platypus is more likely.
Okay. Yeah, platypus, yeah. Platypus is more likely.
Let's just, yeah. これね。そう、これ矛盾よな。
Let's just... This, right? Yeah, this is contradictory.
正解は? ドン! ドン!
The correct answer is? Bam! Bam!
正解は? 正解かどうか? どうだ?
Is it correct? Is it correct or not? How is it?
あひるに告白するスバル。告白する、猫さん?
Subaru confessing to a duck. Confessing, Neko-san?
あんまりしか見てなくて、お盆じゃなくて、あれ挨拶。挨拶だけど...
I only looked at it earlier, it's not a tray, that's a greeting...
なんか、私、告白してるから、顔がハッピーになっちゃったんだよ。
Somehow, since I'm confessing, my face got all happy.
あ、そうそう。It's not a platypus. 圧があるよ、このスバルは。
Ah, right, right. It's not a platypus. There's pressure in this Subaru.
It's not a platypus. なんかゲストがすごいよね、私。うん、ちょっと圧があるね。
It's not a platypus. I look kind of shady. Yeah, there's some pressure.
Yeah, Subaru-senpai is definitely confessing to a duck.
Interesting. Interesting, I know, right?
Well, Mumei, which art do you like the best? Out of this two?
Well, Mumei, which art do you like the best? Out of these two?
一番好きなのは、どれ?
Which one do you like the best?
I have to go with Anya's because I just love the expression that she put on Subaru-senpai.
もう、好きだって。おかしいよ。やっぱ、やっぱね、えごころ。
Saying "I like you", how funny. After all, drawing skills.
絵心がね、もう恵まれてるよ。カモ... カモノハシのほうが...
Drawing skills are so blessed. A pla... A platypus is...
だっで、コマネチしてるよ、これ。これやってほしいわ、スバル先輩に。
Look, she's doing Komaneci. I want Subaru-senpai to do this.
Thank you so much, Mumei. What about you, Zeta?
Okay, for me, I would have to go with Miko-senpai. Look at the beautiful platypus.
これ、かわいいよね、これ。あひる住んでるのに、あひるのこと好きって...
This is so cute, right? Even though she lives with ducks, saying she likes ducks...
別に好きって... みたいさ。別にあひる好きなわけじゃないのかね。
Saying she likes them... Well, maybe she doesn't particularly like ducks.
可愛いよね。いや、別にしてないなら、いや、スバル先輩って。
It's cute. Well, if she's not doing it, I mean, Subaru-senpai.
Oh my god. I thought it was Subaru-senpai scolding the duck.
なんか... なんかあひるに怒ってるみたいな... まあ、確かにね、シュバちゃん、スバルじゃないから。
It feels like... she's mad at the duck... Well, true, it's not really Subaru-chan.
ああ、なるほどね。ちょっと恥ずかしかってんだよね。だよね、やっぱ。可愛いわ。
Ah, I see. She's a bit embarrassed. Right, after all, it's cute.
Thank you so much, Zeta, Mumei for joining us!
あーやさん3Dおめでとう！
Congratulations on your 3D, Anya-san!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ありがと！バイバーイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
いや、みこ先輩もありがと。来てくださって。
Miko-senpai, thank you too for coming.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
いやあ、楽しかったね。
Man, that was fun.
ええ、もう肉終わり？ ええじゃあさ、あの、やっぱそこらへんの武器ちょっと後で持ち帰ってもいいですか？
Yeah, is the meat over? Uh, then can I take some of those weapons home later?
それは、それは、あーやさん、それは、えー、検討しますも。あー、みこ先輩のために、もうぬいぐるみあげたじゃないですか？ まだ欲しい？
That, that... Anya-san, that, um, I'll consider it. Didn't I already give you a plushie for Miko-senpai? You still want more?
え、でも貰ったとき、えー、かっこいいよね、あれね。やっぱ、あー、憧れますよね。
Well, but when I got it, um, it looks cool, right? You know, I really admire it.
え、じゃあ待ってるね。
Oh, then I'll be waiting.
オッケー。
Okay.
うん、じゃあ頑張ってね。
Yeah, then do your best.
おひろめ、ありがと、この後も、ありがとうございます。この後も...
Thanks for the reveal, thank you for after this too. After this too...
この後も頑張りまーす！やったー！
I'll do my best after this too! Yay!
バイバーイ！バイバーイ、みこ先輩！バイバーイ！バイバーイ！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye, Miko-senpai! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
いやあ、でもみこ先輩のイラスト可愛いよね。あー楽しかったなあ、もう。
Man, Miko-senpai's illustration is so cute. Ah, that was so fun.
まだ、まだね、このお披露目はね、続きます。なんと...
But, you know, this reveal is still going. What's more...
さてさて、Let's see, Let's see what is next on our schedule? Wait, what?
Now, now, let's see, let's see what is next on our schedule? Wait, what?
Another, another call? Hello? Hello? Who's coming?
初めまして。え、私、声優の鈴木みのりと申します。
Nice to meet you. Um, I'm voice actress Minori Suzuki.
え、あーやさんがですね、プロジェクト世界の篠のめ絵名がお好きということで、え、こちらでご縁がありましてですね、あの、今回ボイスコメントを送らせていただきたいと思います。
Um, since Anya-san likes Ena Shinonome from Project Sekai, we got connected through that, and, um, I wanted to send a voice comment this time.
まずは、何より、え、3Dお披露目できて、おめでとうございます！
First of all, above all, congratulations on your 3D reveal!
ということで、確かに、私もね、まだあの、このコメントをとっているときは、あーやさんの可愛い、あの、3Dじゃないものを拝見しておりますので、
So, indeed, when I was recording this comment, I was looking at Anya-san's cute, non-3D self,
またこう進化して、ね、3Dのあーやさんになったら、またどんな可愛さが増してしまうんだという感じで、個人的にもワクワクしておりますが、
so I'm personally excited to see how much cuter she'll become once she evolves into a 3D Anya-san,
ええ、そうですね、あーやさんがどんな人なんだろうっていうふうに色々調べていく中で、もちろんあの、YouTubeの方も魅せていただきましたが、
but um, yes, as I was researching what kind of person Anya-san is, I watched your YouTube channel,
あの、「シェーマ」という曲を歌っている動画が私特に好きで、あの、あーやさんのあの、お声、可愛らしいお声とシェーマのあの、キーね、
and I especially love the video where you sing the song "Schema," and I could hear Anya-san's cute voice and Schema's key,
綺麗なあーやさんの裏声も聴けて、なんか、うっとりしちゃうというか、爽やかさと可愛さとカッコよさが同時に楽しめちゃうあーやさんのお歌の上に、
and I could hear Anya-san's pretty falsetto, making me feel enchanted, being able to enjoy the refreshingness, cuteness, and coolness all at once over Anya-san's singing,
1人感動しておりまして、え、ね、絵名をお好きと言ってくださっていて、なんか、こう、演じている身としても、絵名の頑張りが誰かに届いているんだなっていうのを実感できて、
I was moved all by myself, and, you know, since you say you like Ena, as someone who plays her, I could really feel that Ena's hard work is reaching someone,
え、とっても嬉しく思っています。またぜひどこかで、3Dのあーやさんとかとね、あの、お会いできたらいいななんてお話しできたらいいななんてこっそり思ってます。ぜひこれからも頑張ってください、陰ながら応援しております。絵ナのこともしよろしくお願いします。
and I'm very happy about it. I secretly hope that somewhere in the future, I can meet 3D Anya-san and chat. Please keep doing your best, I'm cheering for you from the shadows. Please take care of Ena too.
え、以上、鈴木みのりでした。
Um, that's all, this was Minori Suzuki.
これわ！これはこのあとガチャ回すしかないんですよ！ありがとうございます！
What! This means I have no choice but to roll the gacha after this! Thank you very much!
鈴木みのりさん、ありがとうございます！メッセージ、嬉しい！
Minori Suzuki-san, thank you very much! The message, I'm so happy!
嬉しい。え？ありがとうございます。わっ！
Happy. Eh? Thank you very much. Wah!
What? What happened? What just happened, everyone? What just happened? Who's that? What was that, bro? I'm sorry, I'm sorry guys, I'm winning. I'm winning too much today.
It's not even funny! Excuse me? Who's that? I'm trying to process that.
は？まだあるの？はろー？はろー？止めてください、もう心が、心がもうぐちゃぐちゃになってます、私。誰だ？
Huh? There's more? Hello? Hello? Please stop, my heart is already getting all messed up, me. Who is it?
あーやさん、初めまして。声優の佐倉綾音です。
Anya-san, nice to meet you. I'm voice actress Ayane Sakura.
この度は、まず3Dお披露目おめでとうございます！ホリ、ホリジャコ、ホリヤコってことで、
First of all, congratulations on your 3D reveal! Hori, Horijako, Horiyako, so
どうやら配信などで私の名前をよく出してくださっていたということで、本当にありがとうございます！私も
apparently you've often brought up my name on streams and stuff, so thank you very much! I also...
配信など聞かせていただいたんですけども
I got to listen to your streams and all, but...
とっても可愛い声で佐倉綾音さんが
Sakura Ayane-san has such a cute voice...
「あや、あや、あや、あや」と呼んでいただいていて
calling me "Anya, Anya, Anya, Anya,"
「あぁ、私も明日からお仕事頑張れるな」っていうふうに
and I was like, "Ah, I'll work hard starting tomorrow too!"
思いました。ありがとうございます。
I thought. Thank you very much.
むしろこちらがありがとうございますという気持ちです。
Actually, I feel more like "Thank you very much" instead.
そうですね、アーニャさん、あの私、上坂すみれさんのイラストがとても好きなのですが、その上坂さんがままなんですよね。
That's right, Anya-san... Um, I really love Uesaka Sumire-san's illustrations, and Uesaka-san is your mama, right?
そんな「まいまいつめじ」さんのとっても可愛い上坂さんのイラストに全然負けない、とっても可愛い声で警戒なトーク、楽しい
With such a super cute illustration by "Maimaimetsumeji-san" of Uesaka-san, and a super cute voice with lighthearted, fun talk...
可愛いだけじゃない、面白いトークをされていて、
not just cute, but giving funny talks,
おぉ、すごく素敵だなと思いました。
I thought, "Oh, how wonderful."
日本語もめちゃくちゃお上手ですよねていうか
Your Japanese is also extremely good, I mean...
バイリンガルっていうことになるんですか？
does that make you bilingual?
すっげぇ！私もちんかくこととか、さんかくこととか喋りたくなーるなー。
That's amazing! It makes me want to speak Japanese or trilingual languages too.
あの、たぶん私よりアーニャさんの方が日本語で喋るの上手だと思うんです。
Um, I think Anya-san is probably better at speaking Japanese than I am.
本当にあの、それぐらい、もう、字幕とか全然なしにスムーズに、あの配信を聞かせていただいて
Seriously, like, with zero need for subtitles, I listened to your streams so smoothly
とても楽しませていただきました。ただ、1つ気になったのが
and enjoyed it immensely. However, one thing that caught my attention...
アーニャさんのホロライブの紹介ページあるじゃないですか。
Is on Anya-san's Hololive profile page, right?
そこ紹介欄に「基本的に無感情で人間には特に興味はないです。見た目で判断しないでください。愚かな人間どもはいつも見た目で判断しますよね。」って書いてあるんですよ。
In the description, it says: "Basically emotionless and not particularly interested in humans. Please don't judge by appearances. Foolish humans always judge by appearances, don't they?"
これは、歴史っぽいの？
Is this a historical thing?
私には興味持っていただいたんですよね。
But you showed interest in me, right?
え！？ありがとうございます。もちろん。ですが私が人間扱いされてないっていうことではないんですよね？
Eh!? Thank you very much. Of course. That doesn't mean I'm not being treated like a human, right?
いや女神ですよ。佐倉綾音さんは。ちょっとこれに関して女神でいらっしゃる と私は思っています。開かせることが出来ているんだったら、とっても嬉しい、ありがたいことだなと思いながら読んでおりました。
No, you're a goddess. Sakura Ayane-san. I think of her as a goddess regarding this. I was reading it while thinking how happy and grateful I am if I'm able to make her open up.
あの、人間って、いいものですよ。
Um, humans are good things, you know.
もう知ってるか。知ってますよね、多分素敵な仲間とかリスナーさんに囲まれて知っていると思うんですけど、あのこれからもぜひ引き続き人間のことをよろしくお願いします。
Well, you already know. You know, right? Surrounded by wonderful friends and listeners, I think you know, but please continue to take care of humans from now on.
何の話だ？ということで、アーニャさん、改めて本当に3Dお披露目おめでとうございます！
What am I talking about? With that said, Anya-san, congratulations once again on your 3D reveal!
次は、いつかお喋りできるタイミングが来たら、いやそれ私、多分死にますね。一瞬で死にますね。ありがとうございます。
Next time when the timing comes for us to chat... No, if that happens, I'll probably die in an instant. Thank you very much.
あ、あ、終わっちゃった。終わっちゃった。
Ah, ah, it's over. It's over.
What's that? Of ever dream? What's that? Guys?
うわっ！うら、あく、あく、あく、もう、頭がもう、できない、できない、考えられないよ、ガイーズ、 habis itu. Thank you so much.
Whoa! Whoa, my head is already... I can't, I can't think anymore, guys, habis itu. Thank you so much.
Thank you so much to Sakura Ayane-san and Suzuki Minori-san. あの、鈴木みのりさんも、佐倉綾音さんも、本当にありがとうございます！もうマジで私のなかで、あの熱い声優さんのおふたりでございます。本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much to Sakura Ayane-san and Suzuki Minori-san. Um, Suzuki Minori-san and Sakura-san, thank you very much. Seriously, in my heart, you two are my favorite voice actresses. Thank you truly so much!
ああ、まあ、ということでね、あのこのお披露目はもう私の頭もぐちゃぐちゃになったんですけど、まだ終わって、終わりません、終わりません、終わってないです。
Haah. Well, with that said, um, this reveal completely scrambled my brain, but it's not over yet, it's not over.
まだまだあります！このあと After this, there's still a few more staffs to show you guys. オッケー、let's go to the next live segments, you there? じゃあこのあとのライブパートにうつから、移動します。待っててください！
There's still more! After this, there's still a few more stuffs to show you guys. Okay, let's go to the next live segments, you there? So we'll move on to the next live part. Please wait for me!
うー！
Woo!
はあー。
Haaah...
もう、こんな時間？
Wait, it's this late already?
ああ、私、最近遅れてるなぁ…
Ugh, I've been running late to work these days...
まあ、いいや。
Well, whatever.
アーニャ？アーニャ・メルフィッサ？中にいるわね？おい、アーニャ！！
Anya? Anya Melfissa? I know you're inside. Oi, Anya!!!
(大家さん？)
(...The landlady?)
なんだろ、いっか。
What's up, I wonder...
はーい？
Yeeeees?
アーニャ、もう日付のた、家賃払うぞ、コラ！
Anya... Do you know what date is today already? Pay your damn rent!!
(いや仕事ぼけってないからおカネないんだって！), あらゆるいんね、あこすきすきじょか、じゅが。
(...Ugh, I've been skipping work, too!), Err can I get some pity here?
えーっと、後で払うから勘弁しませんか？
Err, can I get some pity here?
来月までは払うようにしますから...お願いします...？
Like, I can pay next month? Please...?
ダメに決まってるでしょ！！
NO MEANS NO, YOU FREELOADER!!
もうずっと払ってないし
You haven't paid rent for months now,
今日も家賃払わないなら…ここから出てなさい！！！
and if you can't pay today... GET OUT OF HERE!!!
ああぁぁぁぁぁぁぁぁぁぁ!!!
AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAHH!!!
ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、ちょっとまってうわあああああああーーー！！！
W-WAIT, MA'AM, WAIT!!
(人間になるって思った以上に難しいなぁ)
(Being a human is harder than I thought.)
(仕事しなきゃ食べるのもいい場所に住むのも出来ないし。)
(You need to work and do other things just to eat and live in a nice place...)
そんないいいことじゃないかもしれないね、人間になるって。
Maybe being a human was a bad idea all along.
思った以上に闇が深いかも。
It's hard to adapt to their lifestyle.
全く、強くて壮大な古代兵器の私が何故こんな目に？！
I'm a sacred and majestic ancient weapon!
別に面倒くさいことしなくてもいいだろう！
Why should I be doing troublesome things like these?!
…疲れたな。
...I'm getting tired.
とりあえずここで寝よっと…
I'll just sleep on this bench for now...
おやすみ。
Good night.
んー…ん…？
Mmmm... hmm?
えっ！？
HUH!?
…ええっ…？
...Eeeeh...?
Halo. Akhirnya kamu terbangun.
Oh, you're finally awake.
な、なに？
What the hell?
ここどこ？あなた誰？
Where is this? Who are you?
スタジオの前に倒れてるのを見つけたんです。
We found you passed out in front of the studio.
どうも、はじめまして。ミスター85です。
Pleased to meet you, I'm Mr. 85.
とりあえず温かい飲み物をどうぞ。
Here, have a warm drink for now.
ミスター…8…5…？
Mr. 8...5...?
ちょっと怪しいけど…
(Okay, now this IS fishy.)
まあいいや。はじめまして。
Well, nice to meet you too.
こう見えてこれでも兵器で、ここ最近人間になったばかりです。
I might not look like it, but I'm an ancient weapon who just became human.
前のところから追い出されましたけど。
...Well, I got kicked out of my previous place, though.
だからさ！
That's what I've been telling you!
どうして人間ってこんなに残酷なの？
Why are humans so cruel?!
わがままだし、わけかんないし、今の若者の世間ってこんな感じなの？
They're selfish, incomprehensible, are youngsters these days like this?
大変そうですね。
That sounds rough.
でしょ！？もう本当にどうすればいいかすら分かりません！
I know, right?! I really don't know what to do now!
そうですね。
Well...
我々の会社をタレントとして、アイドル活動しませんか？
How about becoming a talent for our agency? An idol.
えっ！？な、なんだって？タレント？
...Eh? What did you say? A talent...?
アイドルVTuberみたいな…
An idol vtuber...?
えっ！？あの人気アイドルVTuber時乃そらみたいに？
EEH? You mean like that popular idol VTuber, Tokino Sora!?
そうですね。彼女も我々のホロライブ所属のタレントです。
Yes. She's also a hololive production talent.
代わりにしばらくの間ここに住んでも構いません。どうですか？
In exchange, you can live here for a while. How does that sound?
やります！やります！やります！
COUNT ME IN!!!
この生活の虜になっちゃうよ lady
I'll make you a captive of this lifestyle, lady.
光を失った
Losing the light,
おさがり宝を
handing down precious stones
永久に纏って
eternally entwined...
救われた日から救いが義務になるなんて
The day we were saved, salvation became a duty,
まるでフィクション トラパネーション 受けた気分になってんだ
like a fiction, a trepanation, feeling as if I've received it.
足枷と腐りに縛られて たった一度の光で逢うため
Bound by shackles and decay, to meet in a single flash of light,
この部屋でずっと忘れた 何かを待つ囚人
a prisoner waiting for something forgotten in this room.
出されたものは満遍なく残さず平らげて
Devouring everything served without leaving a trace,
優等生な屍人 誰よりも無個性だった
an honor-student corpse, lacking individuality more than anyone.
住めば都って暗い歌 また何度も何度も吐き捨てて
Spitting out dark songs of home, time and time again,
挙句の果て食べ切る行為が それ自体苦手になった
until the very act of eating became a chore.
夜中ふと目に映った きらめく仮面の舞踏会
A shimmering masquerade ball catching my eye in the dead of night,
馬鹿らしいほどに 狂おしいほどに 年甲斐も無く惹き込まれたら
so absurdly, so madly drawn in without a care.
この生活の虜になっちゃうよ lady
I'll make you a captive of this lifestyle, lady.
「よく似合ってる」ってさ 「おあつらえ向き」ってさ その後のことは見向きもしないくせに
Saying "it suits you well," saying "how fitting," while completely ignoring what comes next.
この生活の虜になっちゃうよ lady lady
I'll make you a captive of this lifestyle, lady, lady.
痛みだって 癒えぬ傷だって すべて生きてくため乗る越える試練
Even pain, even unhealed wounds, trials to overcome just to live on—
他愛もないことでしょう
it must be nothing special.
少し欠けてる ピンクオパール 迷子になったアイオライト
A slightly chipped pink opal, a lost iolite,
埃を被るトパーズ 孤独のアメトリィみんないる
dusty topaz, lonely ametrine, all dressing up,
それぞれ着飾って 濁って重くなって
growing turbid and heavy,
奈落の底牢獄に 沈んでいくとしても
even if sinking into the prison at the bottom of the abyss.
ああ 訪れた幸せが 祝祭日みたいに
Ah, the visiting happiness, like a holiday,
既に決められた予定調和で
is already a predetermined harmony.
この生活の
This life of mine
虜になっちゃうよ Lady
will make a captive of me, lady.
希望ありきの絶望にさ 依存 依存
Addicted, addicted to despair built on hope...
この生活の
This life of mine
虜になっちゃうよ Lady
will make a captive of me, lady.
いつか報われる 認められてもらえる
"Someday I'll be rewarded," "Someday I'll be recognized"
記憶のメロディ 呪文のように唱えて 己を誤魔化すの
Chanting the melody of memories like a spell to deceive myself.
この生活の
This life of mine
終わりはすぐそこ Lady Lady
is coming to an end very soon, lady, lady.
救いさえただ糧にして
Turning even salvation into mere sustenance,
生きてくため 乗り越える試練 仕様がないことでしょう
overcoming trials just to keep living—it can't be helped, right?
この生活の
This life of mine
虜になっちゃうよ Lady
will make a captive of me, lady.
当たり障りないような大衆的なお先は もう必要はない見送るんだ もう綺麗
I no longer need a harmless, mainstream future; I'll wave goodbye to it all.
この生活の
This life of mine
虜になっちゃうよ Lady
will make a captive of me, lady.
蔑まれてた金にならないがさ
Even if I'm looked down upon for doing what doesn't make money,
琴線を奏でたい言葉は無用
I want to strum heartstrings—words are unnecessary.
この生活の
This life of mine
虜になっちゃうよ Lady Lady
will make a captive of me, lady, lady.
痛みに耐えて 言えぬ秘密も抱いて
Enduring the pain, holding unmentionable secrets,
そう生きてくため纏う者の最後は 他愛もないことでしょう
the end for one who wears such things just to survive—it must be trivial.
あなたも同でしょう
It's the same for you too, right?
イエーイ！
Yay!
わあ！
Wow!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
うるさい！おめでとう！
Shut up! Congratulations!
うるさい！おめでとう！うるさい！
Shut up! Congratulations! Shut up!
生きてくれてありがとう本当に！
Thank you so much for staying alive!
本当に！
Truly!
呼んでくれてありがとうね！
Thank you for inviting me!
ねえ！
Hey!
うん、ねえ！うれしい！
Yeah, hey! I'm so happy!
やっぱ去年ね？
I mean, last year, right?
ねえ。
Yeah.
仲良くなっ、仲良くなった！
We got close, we got so close!
めちゃくちゃ遊んだね！
We hung out a ton, didn't we!
去年ね、あのね、あの、嘘でね？
Last year, you know, like, jokingly?
というね、あのゲームにね、めちゃくちゃ遊ばせていただきました！
We got to play that game so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
いや、ありがとうございます！
Yeah, thank you!
いやでも、あの、ここに呼んだ理由もやっぱ、声が曲に合うと思ったから！
But you know, the reason I invited you is because I thought your voice fit the song so well!
うれしい！
I'm so happy!
やったぜ！
Yes!
めちゃくちゃね、練習しましたよ！
We practiced so much, you know!
いや、ありがとう！めっちゃいい声でしたもう。
Yeah, thank you! It was such a great voice.
小さいな、あの。
So small, um.
いや、そんな、そんな変わらんよ！
No way, we don't look that different!
変わってるよ！結構さ、コンボ、コンボ！
You do! Wait, combo, combo!
いやいや、そんな変わらんって、もう。やっぱこのさ、後ろに飛んでるドローン！
No way, we don't look that different! Besides, that drone flying in the background—
ずっと気になってて！
I've been wondering about it the whole time!
やっぱドローン気になるんだ。
So you were curious about the drone.
気になるよ！結構なになってるんだよね、実の。
Of course! It's actually doing quite a bit, you know.
すごいよね、これね！
It's amazing, really!
ねえ！
Yeah!
こんなね、トンネル、いろいろいいアングルも見せれたんじゃないかな！
We were able to show off all sorts of great tunnel angles, right?
本当に素晴らしい、素敵な！
Truly wonderful and lovely!
感じになったんじゃないですか、ラミィさん。
Don't you think, Lamy-san?
ですね！こちらね、まだまだお披露目、まだまだ続いていくと。
Exactly! This showcase will continue even further.
はい！
Yes!
いうことですね、本当に呼んでてもらって嬉しかったんで、また一緒にどうも！
So, I'm really glad you invited me, let's hang out again—
また行こう！
Let's hang out again!
また遊ぼう！
Let's play again!
また遊ぼうね！
Let's play again, yes!
また遊ぼうね！ルアナも挟んで！
Let's play again with Luna too!
3人でもう、絆あるかどうかわかんないですけど、
The three of us—though I'm not sure if there's any bond between us,
あるよ！だって、あるだろ！
Of course there is! Of course there is!
あるかどうかわかんない、絶対あるよ！
Whether there is or not—definitely!
あります、はい！
There is, yes!
ねえ、次もルーナ先輩と遊びましょう！
Hey, next let's play with Luna-senpai too!
遊びましょう！
Let's play!
それじゃあ、それじゃあ、
Well then, well then,
続きもがんばってねってことで、僕はここでドロンです！
good luck with the rest, so I'm pulling a ninja disappearing act here!
ドロンだ！
Disappearing!
やばいだろう！
That's crazy!
ありがとう！バイバーイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
淡々 言葉を吐いた
Casually spitting out words,
あんな思い出に泣いたのは
crying over such memories—
今日で終わりにしないか
why don't we make today the end?
1,2の合図を待って
Waiting for the 1, 2 signal,
ユーエヌミー手を取り合ったのは僕の勇気ある行動 フェイズ1
You and me holding hands was my courageous action, Phase 1.
淡々 言葉を吐いた
Not really caring, I spat out words
あんな思い出に泣いたのは
Having cried at that memory,
今日で終わりにしないか
Let's put an end to that today
1,2の合図を待って
Wait for the 1, 2
ユーアンドミー 手を取り合ったのは
You and me, holding hands,
僕の勇気ある行動 フェーズ
Was an act prompted by my courage... phase
立ち止まらないでいいんだからね
Since it's fine not to stop, right?
空々しいな この人生
How hypocritical, this life
できないなんて言わないでね
Don't say you can't do it,
今更なんて言わないでね
don't say that now of all times.
僕ら今ささ 環になって
Now, we're in a loop, beginning to spin,
回り始める
starting to rotate.
段階嫌になって でも好きになる
Getting gradually sick of it, but falling in love.
ねぇねぇわかんないや 自己会議も
Hey, hey, I don't get my own self-doubt,
どんどんに寄って でも離れてく
drawing closer step by step, yet drifting apart.
ぱっぱっ音に乗って 踊り始める
Pa, pa, riding along the beat, starting to dance.
散々嫌になって でも好きになる
Getting completely sick of it, but falling in love.
ねぇねぇわかんないや この先もずーっと
Hey, hey, I don't get it, and from here on too,
僕の心をシェイクシェイク イェイ
it makes my heart go shake shake, yay!
大正解なんてないのさ
There's no absolute right answer,
じゃあいったいどこに向かえば
so where on earth should we head?
物語は 終わりますか
Will this story come to an end?
1,2の合図を待って
Wait for the 1, 2
ユーアンドミー 手が触れ合ったのは
You and me, brushing hands,
僕の勇気ある行動 フェーズ
Was an act prompted by my courage... phase
確かまったって 意味ないんだって
Even if it's certain, it means nothing.
恥ずかしがって 夢にバイバイです
Feeling embarrassed, saying bye-bye to dreams.
この先ずっと よろしくね よろしくね
From here on, please treat me well.
君と今ささ 交わって
Now, here we go; I'm connecting with you,
目をそらし合う
averting our eyes together.
段階嫌になって でも好きになる
Getting gradually sick of it, but falling in love.
ねぇねぇわかんないや 自己会議も
Hey, hey, I don't get it at all, this self-doubt,
どんどんに様になって 崩れ落ちてく
steadily becoming aesthetic, crumbling apart.
ぱっぱっ触れる前に 消えてしまうの
Pa, pa, before touching, it vanishes away.
散々嫌になって でも好きになる
Getting completely sick of it, but falling in love.
ねぇねぇわかんないや この先もずーっと
Hey, hey, I don't get it, at this point and forevermore,
わかりあえるまで僕たちは
until we're able to understand each other...
今更なんて言わないでね
Don't say that now of all times,
言わないでね
don't say that.
僕ら今ささ 環になって
Now, we're in a loop, beginning to spin,
回り始める
starting to rotate.
段階嫌になって でも好きになる
Getting gradually sick of it, but falling in love.
ねぇねぇわかんないや 自己会議も
Hey, hey, I don't get my own self-doubt,
どんどんに寄って でも離れてく
drawing closer step by step, yet drifting apart.
ぱっぱっ音に乗って 踊り始める
Pa, pa, riding along the beat, starting to dance.
散々嫌になって でも好きになる
Getting completely sick of it, but falling in love.
ねぇねぇわかんないや この先もずーっと
Hey, hey, I don't get it, and from here on too,
僕の心をシェイクシェイク イェイ
it makes my heart go shake shake, yay!
この先もずーっと
from here on too...
僕の心をシェイクシェイク イェイ
it makes my heart go shake shake, yay!
わー！
Yay!
イェーーーイ！
Woohoo!
3Dおめでとう！
Congratulations on 3D!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
来てくれてありがとう、あーちゃん！
Thank you for coming, Anya!
いや、誘ってくれて、楽しく歌ってくれてありがとう！
No, thank you for inviting me and having fun singing together!
やったぜー！やった！
Yay! We did it!
もう最高に楽しかったですね。
It was super fun!
そうだね、6曲だって。
That's right, six songs.
6曲、めちゃくちゃもう、体がね、止まらないのもん。
Six songs, my body just wouldn't stop moving!
これ、これずっとやってるもん。
We've been doing this the whole time.
あーやが、あーやの手が止まらなくて。
Anya's hands wouldn't stop moving.
やめろ！やめろ！私のまねをやめてよ！
Stop it! Stop copying me!
ってことでね、なんでこの曲を選んだの？
So, why did you choose this song?
えー、だって、わためちゃんにカッコいい曲似合うからね。
Well, because cool songs suit Watame-chan!
うれしーん、え、大丈夫だった？こんなやりたい放題させてくれて。
I'm so happy. Are you sure it was okay to let me do whatever I wanted?
いやいやいやいや、これしか無いやろ！これしかないよな、もう。
No, no, no, this was the only choice! This was definitely it.
ブロックしてこぜ！この後もね！ブロックしていこーぜ！
Let's rock on! Let's keep rocking after this too!
うん、ねえ、私たちもね、あの、気づいたんだけど、
Yeah, you know, we actually realized something...
え？気づいたことがありました。なんと？
Huh? We realized something. What is it?
顔が似てるんだよな！
Our faces look similar!
え？似てる？でかいってことか？
Eh? Similar? You mean big?
いや似てるよね、ほら、見て。ほらほら、似てるよね。
No, they look similar, look. Look, look, they look similar, right?
いや、似てる、で、瞳の色もね、同じだし、紫色だしね。
Well, they're similar, and the eye color is the same too, purple.
ね、顔でかいし！顔でけえ！顔でけえな！
Right, our faces are big! Faces are so big! So big!
もうどっちがでかいのかもうわかんないよ。
I can't even tell which one is bigger anymore.
まあね。
True.
ありがとうね、もう来てくれて嬉しい。
Thank you so much for coming, I'm so happy.
こちらこそだよ。
Likewise!
また遊ぼね！また遊ぼう！
Let's hang out again! Let's play again!
また遊びましょう、またね！もう！
Let's play again, see you! Jeez!
これも、これもぜひね、あのやりたいよね、いつか。やりたい！
We definitely gotta do this sometime too, right? I want to!
こういうゲームあるよね、多分。こういうゲームあるんじゃない？
Games like this exist, right? Probably?
ね、あるある！
Yeah, they do!
やろうよ！いつでも呼んで！来てくれてありがとう！
Let's do it! Call me anytime! Thanks for coming!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
おめでとう！おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations! Congratulations!
あい！
Aye!
おー！
Oh!
うわ！キリト！アグレージェリー3D！3D！
Woah! Kureiji Ollie's 3D! 3D!
オッパイイェーボー！オッパイイェーボー！
Oppai yeah bo! Oppai yeah bo!
おや！リバーシブルとは？あ、リバーシブル？
Oh? What's reversible? Ah, reversible?
なんかみんなのセリフ、サポートコメントとかスーパーチャット、なんかもっときらめくね。
It feels like everyone's supportive comments and super chats are sparkling even more.
オッパイイェーボー！オッパイイェーボー！
Oppai yeah bo! Oppai yeah bo!
え、By the way、みんな知ってるか、これはロゴオパ？
Oh, by the way, guys, do you know what logo this is?
イニイニイニ！ちょっとちょっと待って！ロゴオパだよ！
Ini, ini, ini! Wait, wait, wait! It's a logo!
ロゴオパだよ、じゃん！
It's a logo, ta-da!
あら、TV？あら、TV？
Huh? TV? Huh? TV?
アニャメフィッサ！3Dおめでとう！
Anya Melfissa! Happy 3D!
Ollie, damn those boobs!
Kureiji Ollie, bagaimana tadi? Kita... joget dan nyanyi—enggak nyanyi sih, joget tapi ke-identity crisis.
Kureiji Ollie, how was it? We danced and sang—well, didn't sing, just danced—with an identity crisis.
How was that? Wah, baru tau loh bisa nge-DJ.
How was that? Wow, I never knew you could DJ.
Salah satu my hidden skills, well, I've been living for like hundreds of years. Dan Pavolia Reine bagaimana tadi?
One of my hidden skills, well, I've been living for like hundreds of years. And Pavolia Reine, how was it?
Tadi? Kita ngapain aja ya, langsung? Saking hartenya lupa kita ngapain. Kita nge-DJ dan berjoget.
Just now? What did we even do? We were having so much fun we forgot. We DJ'd and danced.
By the way itu udah berkilau! Kaca saya, kaca saya, makasih! Thank you, thank you, terima kasih!
By the way, it's already sparkling! My glass! My glass! Thanks! Thank you, thank you, terima kasih!
Ya udah berarti gitu aja ya? Hah? Enggak, bukan gitu dong!
So that's it then? Huh? No, that's not it!
Kita kan, ini udah di-stage bertiga, kita mau nyanyi dan nge-DJ bareng!
We're all three on stage together now, we're gonna sing and DJ together!
Yes, kita atur formasi dulu... Listen to our cover song, I guess.
Yes, let's arrange our formation first... Listen to our cover song, I guess.
ガラクタばかりを集めて
Collecting only scraps and junk,
ボロ切れひとつを被せた
draping a single tattered rag over them,
醜い形をしたレプリカ
a replica shaped in an ugly form.
誰かが紡いだ言葉を
Words spun by someone,
誰かが奏でた音色を
tones played by someone,
歪にコラージュした偽物
a fake distortedly collaged together.
一番最初はベールの中革新的な少年の愛情が
At the very beginning, inside the veil, a revolutionary boy's affection
僕ら気付いたらもう見えなくなる
before we knew it, becomes invisible to us.
おもちゃを無くした子供が泣いている
A child who lost their toy is crying.
どうしようだろうか？あのスポットライトに
What should we do? Underneath that spotlight,
照らされているその背中は
that back being illuminated
またこの手から遠ざかっていく
is drifting further away from these hands once again.
あなたみたいになれやれなくて
Not being able to become like you,
あつい雲を引っ裂いて 月明かり足下を照らす
Ripping apart thick clouds, moonlight illuminates our feet.
渇いた心は満たされないまま
My thirsty heart remains unfulfilled.
一人になって一人になってくすんだ夢を見つめ続けてしまった
Being alone, I kept staring at faded dreams.
僕たちは
We...
巡りだって彷徨ぎだってその心は絶えず光るには僕だけの光があった
Wandering and straying, in order to shine constantly, there was a light only mine.
足りないのなんだってんだろう 髪々に聞いた木陰で
What could be lacking? In the shade of trees where I asked.
黄昏の弓矢に口止めされた
I was silenced by the arrow of twilight.
初めて知っていたんだよ 忘れたふりをもしてんだよ
I knew it from the start, pretending to have forgotten.
もらい物の剣を抱きしめている
I am holding tight to a borrowed sword.
何回かいやも失望だったの一その身にも過ちを犯してしまいたいと
How many times was it disappointment, wanting to commit a sin in that very body?
究極最後には何も残らない 愛を紡いでも名前を消していく
Ultimately, nothing is left; even as we weave love, our names fade away.
どうしてだろうこの胸の奥にこびり付いている
Why is it that deep inside this chest it clings—
冬の夜の七日間に似た孤独を
a loneliness resembling the seven days of a winter night?
あなたはきっと知りもしないで
You surely without ever knowing—
一人星を見ていた
watching the stars alone.
赤い目の僕に気も留めないまま
Remaining indifferent to me with my red eyes.
隣に立ったあなたは遠くて くすんだ夢も見えなくなってしまって
Standing beside me, you were so far away that I could no longer see our faded dreams.
それをも追い続けて
Continuing to chase even that.
世物のだって本当だって もし振り返れば そこにはぼやけた記憶があった
Whether fake or real, if I looked back, there was a blurred memory there.
罪悪と化したアイロニ クリシェを抜け出したいのに
Wanting to break free from the irony and cliché turned into guilt,
また誰かの焼き直し？
just a retelling by someone else again?
数々の星のかけらたち 沈みゆく夕せいに 無慈悲な月の光
Countless fragments of stars sinking into the fading twilight, the merciless moonlight.
アイデンティティーのまかし
A phantom of identity.
盗んでもでも愛が欲しい
Even if I steal it, I want love.
羊のような雲浮かぶ昼過ぎ
Past noon, with sheep-like clouds floating by,
懐かしい歌が風に揺れている
a nostalgic song sways in the wind.
新たな恋人を知ってもらったことは 今でも忘れないように書き留めてる同じことを
To ensure I never forget even now that you learned of my new lover, I write down the same thing.
あなたみたいになりやしたくて あの日を追いかけて
Wanting to become like you, chasing after that day.
渇いた心は満たされないまま 時間が経って時間が経って振り返る時目をそますように覗う僕たちは
My thirsty heart remaining unfulfilled, as time passes and I look back, we gaze as if averting our eyes.
忘れたってだってさ 冷めの夢を ぜいたく先には僕だけの光がずっと
Even if forgotten, waking dreams— ahead of that luxury, my own light is always...
ああ、お疲れ！みんな！うーん、ギターほろろ、歌う、一緒にさ、で、DJ一緒。
Ah, good job everyone! Um, playing guitar, singing together, and DJing together.
Okay, we sang Gekkou, Reine and I sang Gekkou. How was it? It's one of my favorite songs, and I'm so happy I got to sing it with them.
まあ、いろいろありましたね。カナタ先輩とね、あの、一緒にドロンしたし、まあ私はドロンしてなかったんですけど。
Well, a lot happened. Kanata-senpai and I did a ninja vanish together... well, I actually didn't ninja vanish.
でも、ワタメちゃんともね、あの、ベースもね、もう、こんなにもね、あの、引きましたね。
But with Watame-chan too, you know, the bass was really played like this.
いやあ、楽しかった！で、IDにキセーと一緒にDJ、そして、え、Gekkou歌いましたと、いかがでしたでしょうか？ How was it everyone?
Man, it was fun! And with ID 1st gen, DJing together, and then singing Gekkou, how was it everyone?
まあ、この後もね、いろいろまだあるので、After this, there's still some stuff that I want to show you guys. Oh my goodness!
Well, after this there's still more to come, so after this there's still some stuff that I want to show you guys. Oh my goodness!
あれ？あれ？ん？ What is it? What's that sound? Hello? Wait, what? What is that? Something is flying? Wait, what? Huh?
Huh? Huh? What? What is that sound? Hello? Wait, what? What is that? Something is flying? Wait, what? Huh?
か、,なんか、見たこと、ファミリア、 guys? あれ？あれ？知る顔だぞ？え？
Wh-, it looks familiar, guys? Huh? Huh? I know that face? Eh?
ちょっと、ちょっと、み、見てみたい。あれ？ちょっと近く、近くから見てみたい。あれ？ Is that? Wait, is that YAGOO? Is that YAGOO?
Wait, wait, I wanna see. Huh? Let's look closer. Huh? Is that? Wait, is that YAGOO? Is that YAGOO?
あれ？あ、YAGOOじゃん、みんな！ YAGOOの、YAGOOにも愛音同コチャック？ YAGOO本気じゃん！
Huh? Ah, it's YAGOO, everyone! YAGOO, YAGOO is even flying? YAGOO is for real!
YAGOO！YAGOOさん、こっち、こっち！
YAGOO! YAGOO-san, over here, over here!
YAGOO！YAGOOの、みせまえ？ YAGOO！ほんとらんや！
YAGOO! YAGOO's... YAGOO! For real!
あれ 一体 何が… あれ? YAGOOさんですよね?
Huh? What on earth... Huh? It's YAGOO, right?
飛べるんですか?
Can you fly?
そうですね、アニャさん、3Dお披露目おめでとうございます。
That's right. Anya-san, congratulations on your 3D reveal.
ええっ! もしかして今日わざわざここまで? ありがとうございます!
Eh?! Did you actually come all the way here today? Thank you so much!
せっかくなので、まあ我々ホロライブID 2期生はね、3Dお披露目をしたわけなんですけれども、YAGOOさんのご感想をお聞きしたいのですが、いただいてもよろしいですか?
Since we have the chance, I'd love to hear your thoughts, YAGOO. May I?
ホロライブインドネシアの皆さんも、1期生に続いて2期生の皆さんも、3Dお披露目ができてとてもよかったと思います。
I think it's wonderful that both Gen 1 and Gen 2 could have their 3D reveals.
おおっ! あれっ、ありがとうございます! あれ、大丈夫かな、これYouTube的に。大丈夫かな?
Whoa! Oh, thank you! Wait, is this okay for YouTube? Will it be fine?
まあ、そうですね、ありがとうございます!
Well, um, yeah, thank you very much!
最後に、えーっと、今日の晩ご飯何を食べたか教えていただきたいです。
Lastly, um, could you tell us what you had for dinner today?
今日は奥さんの手料理を食べました。
Today, I had my wife's home-cooked meal.
ほお、幸せそうですね、声から。いやあ、ありがとうございました! 以上です、お帰り気をつけてくださーい!
Ohh, you sound so happy! Well, thank you very much! Have a safe trip home!
ばいばい! YAGOO、YAGOOさん! ばいばい! YAGOOさん、ありがとう! 来てくれて! Thank you!
Bye-bye! YAGOO, YAGOO-san! Thank you for coming! Thank you!
あー、Oh my god! I can't believe YAGOO actually visited!
Ah, oh my god! I can't believe YAGOO actually visited!
Gila, dari YAGOO sampai datang! Gila banget, sich, guys!
Crazy, YAGOO actually came! That's insane, guys!
Anyways, I still have like some more things to show to you guys. So, let's go to the next stage! いや、次のステージに移動しようかな! 次は!
Anyways, I still have more to show you. Let's go to the next stage! Next is...
IDアリーナだー!
ID Arena!
うわ、ぎゃ、ステージ替わり! わあ、IDアリーナの、アニャ・メルフィッサどん! ステージ誰ほー!
Whoa, stage change! It's Anya Melfissa's ID Arena stage! Whose stage is next? Woo!
Welcome to ID Arena, Anya Melfissa version! This is my ID Arena stage, and I will be singing a special song. あく、ここに、あかん、歌うや、 गाइस、歌う、あっぱ!
Welcome to ID Arena, Anya Melfissa version! And I will be singing a special song.
Well, my, my original song! で、ここで何するかと言うと、ええ、1曲ね、歌います。何の曲なのかね、あの、私のあのオリジナル曲、初のオリジナル曲、My first original song, please listen to it. Unreal Veil!
Well, my original song! My first original song, please listen to it. Unreal Veil!
どっからどう見ても品行方正
No matter how you look at it, I'm well-behaved,
いったって真面目でいいじゃんね
acting earnest is totally fine, right?
メガネかけ歩く天真爛漫
Wearing glasses, walking innocently,
本当の自分かわからない?
Don't even know my true self?
マスクをつけて隠してる
Putting on a mask to hide it all,
泣きそうな顔全部隠してる
hiding every tearful face away.
夜が来るたびに思い出してる
Remembering it every time night comes,
空駆ける秀麗で隠してく
hiding it with soaring grace.
もううんざりかい?
Are you sick of it already?
アンリアル絡まって叫いじゃおうぜ
Let's tangle in the unreal and shout it out!
隠してた本当の自分を
The true self we've been hiding,
ある観客にならないで
don't just be a spectator—
甘い嘘も本当にしよう
let's make sweet lies reality.
(本当のヴェール) 可愛く笑って
(True veil) Smile cutely,
(嘘つきヴェール) 楽しく笑って
(Liar's veil) Smile happily,
(本当のヴェール) きみが笑っている
(True veil) You are smiling,
アンリアルヴェール
Unreal Veil.
コードの上を伝っていくんだ
Walking along the chord,
ひとつの眉も揺らさずに
without even twitching an eyebrow.
夜が来たならば明朗せいだい
If night comes, be loud and clear,
嫌いなものは捨て立ちゃまえ
toss away whatever you hate.
オッケーさあびびっちぇんな気にするな
Okay, come on, don't cower or care,
秘密あんなんて気にするな
don't worry about having secrets.
一瞬で判断せーの走り出すんだ
Decide in an instant and start running,
正解は自分で決めろ神様
decide the right answer yourself, God!
案外弱いみたいな真相
A truth that seems surprisingly weak,
全部さらけ出しでしまいな
just bare it all out there.
散々悩んだって一人きりじゃアンサー出ないよ
No matter how much you worry alone, no answer comes.
(say ho) (say ho)
悪いことしたら神様が見てる?
Did something bad? Is God watching?
なんて嘘なんじゃないなんて聞いてない
What a lie, I'm not listening to that.
神すら見透かせないfake fake
A fake that even God can't see through, fake, fake.
真実がないなんて誰も言ってない
Nobody's saying there is no truth.
燦々揺れるマスクをとって
Take off the brightly swaying mask,
どっからどう見ても品行方正
No matter how you look at it, exemplary conduct,
いたって真面目いいじゃんね
completely serious, isn't that fine?
メガネかけ歩き天真爛漫
Walking with glasses, naive and innocent,
本当の自分わからない？
don't you know your true self?
マスクを着けて隠している
Hiding it by wearing a mask,
泣きそうな顔全部隠している
hiding every tearful face completely.
夜が来るたびに思い出している
Remembering every time night comes,
空かける秀麗で隠してく
hiding it with a soaring beauty.
もううんざりかい？
Are you already fed up?
アンリアル絡まって叫びおこうぜ
Entangled in unreality, let's shout it out,
隠してた本当の自分を
our true selves that we've been hiding!
ある観客になんないで
Don't just become a mere spectator,
甘い嘘も本当にしよう
let's make sweet lies true as well.
(本当のヴェール) 可愛く笑って
(True veil) Smiling cutely,
(嘘つきヴェール) 楽しく笑って
(Liar's veil) Smiling happily,
(本当のヴェール) きみが笑っている アンリアルな今日を
(True veil) You are smiling, through this unreal day,
戦うんだ
fighting on!
コードの上を伝っていくんだ
Tracing along the code,
一つの眉も揺らさずに
without shaking even a single eyebrow.
夜が来るならば公明正大
If night comes, fair and square,
嫌いなものは捨てちまえ
throw away whatever you dislike.
オッケーさびびってんな気にすんな
Okay, don't cower, don't worry about it,
秘密があんのなんて気にするんな
don't worry about having secrets either.
一瞬で判断せーの走り出すんだ
Deciding in an instant, setting off to run,
正解は自分で決めろ神様
decide the correct answer yourself, God.
案外弱いみたいな真相
A truth that seems unexpectedly fragile,
全部さらけ出してしまいたいな
I want to expose it all completely.
散々悩んだってさ
No matter how much you agonize over it,
一人じゃアンサー出ないよ
you won't find the answer alone.
say ho!
悪いことしたら神様が見てる？ (no)
If you do something bad, does God see you? (No)
なんて嘘なんじゃない？ なんて聞かない
As if that's a lie? I won't ask.
うわー！ How was that?
Whoa! How was that?
My first original song, Bagaimana Guys?
Original song pertama aku, bagi yang sering nanyain, ori song mana Anya?
My very first original song, for those who kept asking, "Where's Anya's original song?"
Gimana, gimana, keren banget kan?
How was it? Wasn't it super cool?
And oh my god, do you guys know that that same original song will be digitally releasing?
And oh my God, do you guys know that that same original song will be digitally released?
Here's the jacket!
アンリアルヴェイル、作曲へぼっちぼろまるさんの「アンリアルヴェイル」え私の初のオリ曲でございます。
"Unreal Veil," composed by Bocchi Boromaru, "Unreal Veil," is my very first original song.
デジタルリリース決定！
Its digital release is confirmed!
It will be digitally releasing at July 29th at 0 AM your timezone.
It will be digitally released on July 29th at 0:00 AM in your time zone.
えデジタルリリースなんですけど夜中のね、あの0時え29日夜中の0時ね、あの決定いたします。
It's a digital release at midnight, you know, at midnight on the 29th, it has been decided.
さらに、Not only that, but also my second original song will be digitally releasing as well!
Furthermore, not only that, but also my second original song will be digitally released as well!
Not only one song, but two! Two songs! さらに、え、あの、第2のオリ曲もね、
Not only one song, but two! Two songs! Furthermore, my second original song too—
え、あの、同じ時間でデジタルリリース決定！え、楽曲ユノスケさんです。
It's also decided for a digital release at the same time! Composed by Yunosuke.
作曲ユノスケさんの、え、「Everlasting knife」! Woo!
Composed by Yunosuke, "Everlasting knife"! Woo!
Not only one original songs, but two! Oh my goodness, spicy! And also it's not ending yet.
Not only one original song, but two! Oh my goodness, spicy! And also it's not ending yet.
I have a special teaser for you guys. Here it is!
「アンリアルヴェイル」 Vocal by Anya Melfissa Lyrics by ぼっちぼろまる Composed by ぼっちぼろまる Arranged by HAMA-kgn (Felion Sounds)
[Title: "Unreal Veil" / Vocal: Anya Melfissa / Lyrics & Music: Bocchi Boromaru]
Digital Release : 2023.7.29 00:00 (土) MV Release : 2023.8.03 21:00 (木)
[Digital Release: July 29, 2023, 0:00 / MV Release: August 3, 2023, 21:00]
Oh my god, are you winning, malfriends? Oh my goodness, my original song MV will be premiering at August 3rd!
Oh my god, are you winning, my friends? Oh my goodness, my original song MV will be premiering on August 3rd!
え、オリ曲のMVはですね、なんと8月3日にプレミア公開決定でございます！うー！
Um, the original song MV's premiere is decided for August 3rd! Woo!
Please wait for more info about it, hehehehe. And also, one more announcement, what is it? Here it is!
Please wait for more info about it, hehe. And also, one more announcement, what is it? Here it is!
わい！あのグッズ、めちゃくそ可愛いよ！さらに、えっと、ちょっと待ってくださいね。なんとですね、なんとですね、
Yay! That merch is super cute! Also, um, please wait a second. Guess what, guess what—
実物も今持っています。This cushion, so cute! It will be on sale tomorrow after the hololo mini live by the way.
I'm actually holding the real thing right now. This cushion, so cute! It will be on sale tomorrow after the hololive mini-live, by the way.
え、明日のね、あの、ID2期生のミニライブ後でね、あの、発売でございます。アーニャメルフィッサスペシャルクッション、so cute!
Um, tomorrow after ID Gen 2's mini-live, it will go on sale. Anya Melfissa Special Cushion, so cute!
やあ、楽しみだね。And also, don't forget everyone tomorrow, hololo mini live ada, hololo mini live ya besok guys, jangan lupa.
Yeah, looking forward to it. And also, don't forget everyone tomorrow, there's a hololive mini-live tomorrow, guys, don't forget.
And yeah, that's it! Oh my god, thank you so much. Thank you so much everyone for supporting till the end. Thank you, thank you.
いや、こんな感じの3Dお披露目でございます。
Yeah, this is what my 3D showcase was like.
いや、本当にみんなありがとう！ Thank you so much everyone! And I'll see you guys tomorrow with Ollie and Reine.
Yeah, truly, thank you everyone! Thank you so much everyone! And I'll see you guys tomorrow with Ollie and Reine.
あしたのね、あの、ミニライブもよろしくお願いします！いや、感動するね。
Tomorrow's mini-live too, please look forward to it! Man, it's so touching.
No! Oh my god!
Well, but that's it.
That's it for me.
I will be signing out.
See you guys tomorrow!
And...
Arigatou cris!
Arigatou cris Anya, arigatou cris everyone.
Minasan, arigatou cris desu!
Bye-bye!
Arigatou cris!
THANK YOU.
THIS WILL BE AN UNFORGETTABLE DAY OF MY ANCIENT WEAPON LIFE.
PLEASE KEEP ON SUPPORTING ME <3
3D SHOWCASE
#AnyaMelfissa3D